<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Daring Fireball</title>
<subtitle>By John Gruber</subtitle>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/" />
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main" />
<id>https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main</id>


<updated>2018-04-28T00:01:31Z</updated><rights>Copyright © 2018, John Gruber</rights><entry>
	<title>The Talk Show: ‘$270 Worth of Unneeded Keyboards’</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2018/04/27/ep-220" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quv" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/the-talk-show-220" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34807</id>
	<published>2018-04-28T00:01:29Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-28T00:01:31Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Special guest Jim Dalrymple returns to the show. Topics include the litany of problems with MacBook keyboards, speculation regarding why Apple’s AirPower multi-device charging mat still isn’t shipping, Google’s proposal to replace SMS with a new protocol that isn’t encrypted, and more.</p>

<p>Sponsored by:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://alexweinstein.com/thetalkshow">Alex Weinstein Music</a>: A carefully curated collection of just a few hundred songs from one composer available for you to license.</li>
<li><a href="https://squarespace.com/talkshow">Squarespace</a>: Make your next move. Use code <strong>talkshow</strong> for 10% off your first order.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained">Vox’s new Today Explained podcast</a>: Subscribe today in <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297?mt=2">Apple Music</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1346207297/today-explained">Overcast</a>, <a href="http://pca.st/todayexplained">Pocket Casts</a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts.</li>
</ul>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Talk Show: &#8216;$270 Worth of Unneeded Keyboards&#8217;’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/the-talk-show-220">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Gus Mueller: ‘Apple Should Make an Instagram Clone’</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://shapeof.com/archives/2018/4/apple_instagram_clone.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quu" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/mueller-instagram-clone" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34806</id>
	<published>2018-04-27T22:47:18Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-27T22:47:19Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Gus Mueller:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Instagram is one of the last social networks I use these days,
which I actually enjoy visiting. But I always get a little twitchy
using it because it&#8217;s owned by Facebook (which I&#8217;m really not a
fan of). And the ads are getting pretty annoying these days.</p>

<p>So wouldn&#8217;t it be awesome if Apple made a privacy focused clone of
it? I know Apple doesn&#8217;t really do well when it comes to social
services, but I&#8217;m wondering if a simple photo sharing site might
not be impossible for them to do well.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking about this ever since Mueller posted this a week ago. I think this could be great. At a technical level, <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/eddy-cue-200k-imessages-per-second-2016-2">iMessage shows</a> that Apple can build a system that scales. The biggest problem I can think of is usernames. Apple IDs don&#8217;t have to be icloud.com / me.com / mac.com usernames &#8212; you can use any email address. And you wouldn&#8217;t want to expose your email and iMessage address publicly. But Game Center uses nicknames to avoid the same problem. Apple could either piggyback on Game Center nicknames, or set up a new namespace of nicknames for this hypothetical Instagram clone.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Gus Mueller: &#8216;Apple Should Make an Instagram Clone&#8217;’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/mueller-instagram-clone">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Katie Notopoulos: ‘I’m Sorry to Report Instagram Is Bad Now’</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/katienotopoulos/what-if-instagram-is-bad-now?utm_term=.rpx6m4AZE#.xkG5Q3OKr" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qut" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/notooulos-instagram" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34805</id>
	<published>2018-04-27T22:39:19Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-27T22:39:20Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Katie Notopoulos, writing at BuzzFeed:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Look, I don’t want to talk about this any more than you do. I
didn’t want this to be true. I wanted this to work out; I thought
this was the platform that could be The One to make it with us for
the long haul. But it’s time to get real. It’s not working out.
Instagram kind of sucks now. And it’s not Instagram, it’s not us,
it’s an outside force that is tearing us apart. That homewrecker
is Stories.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I found myself nodding my head in agreement throughout &#8212; and she doesn&#8217;t even mention the non-linear algorithmic timeline.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Katie Notopoulos: &#8216;I’m Sorry to Report Instagram Is Bad Now&#8217;’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/notooulos-instagram">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Samsung Sees Slow Demand for OLEDs Used for Apple’s iPhone X</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-26/samsung-sees-slow-demand-for-oleds-used-for-apple-s-iphone-x" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qus" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/samsung-oleds" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34804</id>
	<published>2018-04-27T17:54:57Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-27T22:25:01Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Gurman and Sam Kim, reporting for Bloomberg:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Samsung Electronics Co. is the latest Apple Inc. supplier to offer
a sign of weaker iPhone X sales, saying that it’s seeing slow
demand for the screens used in the flagship product.</p>

<p>The South Korean electronics manufacturer said in an earnings
report today that profits for its display business “were affected
by slow demand for flexible OLED panels.” The division’s sales
rose 3.4 percent in the latest quarter, compared with 20 percent
for Samsung as a whole.</p>

<p>Flexible OLED panels are the screens used inside the iPhone X, and
those are supplied exclusively by Samsung. Other component makers
for Apple, which reports quarterly earnings results next week,
have also issued gloomy outlooks pointing to lackluster demand for
the top-end phone.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Starting to sound like iPhone X sales really are falling short of expectations. You often can&#8217;t judge iPhone sales from the perspective of a component maker, because Apple could have switched to another company for the same component. But these flexible OLED displays <em>only</em> come from Samsung. Apple reports earnings for the first calendar quarter on Tuesday.</p>

<p>My spitball theory: the iPhone X is not &#8220;too expensive&#8221;, but it is too expensive for mass market casual phone buyers. <a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2018/02/apple-reports-its-holiday-2017-earnings-today/">iPhone sales always peak in the fourth calendar quarter</a> by a large margin, for two reasons: (1) it&#8217;s the holiday quarter, so anyone buying an iPhone as a gift is going to buy it in November or December; and (2) that&#8217;s the first full quarter when new top-tier iPhones debut, and enthusiasts buy them as soon as they can. <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/18/02/01/tim-cook-iphone-x-top-selling-iphone-every-week-since-it-shipped-in-november">iPhone X sales were great in the holiday quarter</a>, but perhaps the enthusiasm of the early adopter crowd isn&#8217;t shared by the mass market.</p>

<p>Perhaps I&#8217;m just stating the obvious here &#8212; the existence of the iPhone 8 and 8 Plus indicates that Apple anticipated the need for brand new high-end iPhones in the $700-800 price range. Assuming they keep going with the new $1000-1100 tier, those phones might be even <em>more</em> biased toward the holiday quarter than other iPhones.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/mgsiegler/status/989929634887237634">M.G. Siegler</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Good points, and the flip side of why the iPhones 8 didn’t sell as
well out of the gate: the early-adopters/die-hard were waiting for
X. In an ideal world, the releases would have been inverted (X
first, 8 a couple months later).</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Samsung Sees Slow Demand for OLEDs Used for Apple&#8217;s iPhone X’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/samsung-oleds">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>3D Touch Needs to Be Pervasive</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.macrumors.com/2018/04/26/kuo-no-3d-touch-6-1-inch-2018-iphone/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qur" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/3d-touch-pervasive" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34803</id>
	<published>2018-04-27T17:25:21Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-27T22:25:14Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Juli Clover, writing for MacRumors:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Kuo says that the 6.1-inch iPhone will use what he calls &#8220;Cover
Glass Sensor&#8221; (CGS) technology, relocating the iPhone&#8217;s touch
module from the display panel (in-cell technology) to the surface
glass. The CGS method reportedly results in a display that&#8217;s
lighter and more shock resistant.</p>

<p>With this display technology, Apple will add a thin-film sensor to
the touch film sensor included in the CGS, but the purpose of the
new layer is unknown. It will, however, result in a 15 percent
increase in the cost of the touch panel, resulting in a higher
purchase price of $23 to $26.</p>

<p>To offset the cost of the new display it plans to use, Kuo
believes Apple will remove the 3D Touch functionality on the
6.1-inch iPhone, which would be a curious move as 3D Touch is
well-integrated throughout the operating system that runs on the
iPhone at this point.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I don&#8217;t generally link to rumors like this, but this one caught my eye because I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about 3D Touch lately. 3D Touch is the sort of feature that either needs to be on <em>all</em> iPhones or else should be dropped. If it&#8217;s not pervasive across the entire platform, developers can&#8217;t count on it. I think that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s underutilized today. But it&#8217;s one thing to wait for older iPhones from the pre-3D Touch era to drop out of usage. It&#8217;s another for Apple to sell a brand new phone in 2018 without it. I&#8217;m not going to rant and rave about something that&#8217;s only a rumor &#8212; but if September rolls around and Apple ships this new phone without 3D Touch to save a few measly dollars, I&#8217;m going to rant and rave.</p>

<p>I also think it&#8217;s a serious problem that iPhones have 3D Touch and iPads don&#8217;t, yet iPads are stuck running an OS where 3D Touch is the way to bring up a contextual shortcut menu, but that&#8217;s a different rant.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘3D Touch Needs to Be Pervasive’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/27/3d-touch-pervasive">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>The Fonts of Google Tasks</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://pxlnv.com/linklog/google-tasks/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quq" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/26/heer-google-tasks" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34802</id>
	<published>2018-04-26T18:23:22Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-26T18:23:23Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Nick Heer, writing at Pixel Envy about Google&#8217;s new Google Tasks app:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It isn’t just about what these typefaces look like, either, but
how they’re used. For example, when entering a new task, the name
of the task is set in Product Sans; when it is added to the list,
it becomes Roboto. Tapping on the task takes you to a details view
where, now, the name of the task is in Product Sans. There are
three options to add more information: if you want to add details,
you’ll do it in Roboto, but adding a due date will be in Product
Sans. The “add subtasks” button &#8212; well, text in the same grey as
everything else except other buttons that are blue &#8212; is set in
Product Sans, but the tasks are set in Roboto.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Such an odd inattention to detail.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Fonts of Google Tasks’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/26/heer-google-tasks">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>30 Years of Frontier</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://scripting.com/2018/04/18/164609.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qup" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/30-years-of-frontier" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34801</id>
	<published>2018-04-25T20:08:35Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-25T20:08:37Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Dave Winer:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Little-known fact: I designed and developed a programming
language.</p>

<p>My goal was to create an environment I would work in for the rest
of my career. I just realized it&#8217;s exactly <em>30 years later</em>, and
I&#8217;m still using it.</p>

<p><em>30 fucking years</em>. I think I earned the right to say it that way.</p>

<p>Now that I also work in JavaScript, it amazes me how easy the
simple things are in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UserLand_Software">Frontier</a>, compared to JS, esp when you have
to tack on a database. You really have to work at seeing what&#8217;s
going on. In Frontier, you just click around expanding things. You
can even look at the runtime stack that way.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If you never used Frontier, it&#8217;s hard to explain what made it so special. My very favorite thing about Frontier is the &#8220;object database&#8221;. It wasn&#8217;t like using a database in the SQL sense. It was just persistent storage. You didn&#8217;t have to deal with the file system at all. You just wrote to, say, <code>scratchpad.foo</code> or <code>examples.bar</code> or any other unique identifier and whatever you wrote would be there when you went to read it. And, even better, there was a visual interface for exploring everything in the object database. You could see it and explore it, because in addition to being a language, Frontier was also a real Mac app. You could even customize the app&#8217;s menu items just by editing the <code>system.misc.menubar</code> table in the object database. It&#8217;s a wonderfully self-contained design. <a href="http://scripting.com/frontier/manual/chapter06.html">Re-reading the documentation</a> makes me wonder why there&#8217;s nothing like Frontier&#8217;s object database in other scripting languages.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘30 Years of Frontier’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/30-years-of-frontier">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Tim Cook and Lisa Jackson Attend President Trump’s First State Dinner</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/18/04/24/tim-cook-and-lisa-jackson-attend-president-trumps-first-state-dinner" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quo" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/cook-jackson-state-dinner" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34800</id>
	<published>2018-04-25T19:01:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-25T19:01:01Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-25/apple-s-cook-to-meet-with-trump-amid-u-s-china-trade-tensions">Cook met with Trump</a> in the White House this afternoon, ostensibly to talk about trade policy.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Tim Cook and Lisa Jackson Attend President Trump&#8217;s First State Dinner’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/cook-jackson-state-dinner">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Casey Johnston Gives Up on the Current MacBook Pro Keyboard</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://theoutline.com/post/4277/dont-buy-the-new-macbook-pros-even-on-sale-in-my-opinion" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qun" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/johnston-mbp-keyboard" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34799</id>
	<published>2018-04-25T18:09:22Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-25T18:48:48Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Casey Johnston, writing for The Outline:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A few months ago, I wrote about how my one-year-old MacBook Pro&#8217;s
keyboard keys stopped working <a href="https://theoutline.com/post/2402/the-new-macbook-keyboard-is-ruining-my-life?zd=1&amp;zi=cseimgyt">if a single piece of dust slipped
under there</a>, and more importantly, that neither Apple nor its
Geniuses would acknowledge that this was actually a problem.
Today, Best Buy announced it is having a significant sale on these
computers, marking them hundreds of dollars off. Interesting.
Still, I’d suggest you do not buy them.</p>

<p>Since I wrote about my experience, many have asked me what
happened with the new top half of the computer that the Apple
Geniuses installed, with its pristine keyboard and
maybe-different key switches. The answer is that after a couple
of months, I started to get temporarily dead keys for seemingly
no reason. Again.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This keyboard has to be one of the biggest design screwups in Apple history. Everyone who buys a MacBook depends upon the keyboard and this keyboard is undependable.</p>

<p><a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2018/04/casey-johnston-dont-buy-the-macbook-pros-even-on-sale/">Jason Snell</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I know that we Apple-watchers sit around wondering if Apple will
release new laptops with new keyboards that don’t have these
issues, but Apple’s relative silence on this issue <em>for existing
customers</em> is deafening. If these problems are remotely as common
as they seem to be, this is an altogether defective product that
should be recalled.</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Casey Johnston Gives Up on the Current MacBook Pro Keyboard’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/johnston-mbp-keyboard">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Nvidia Tegra Flaw Allows Nintendo Switch to Be Jailbroken</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/24/17276214/nintendo-switch-hack-jailbreak-security-homebrew-apps-games" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qum" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/nintendo-switch-hack" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34798</id>
	<published>2018-04-25T16:45:58Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-25T16:46:00Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Tom Warren, writing for The Verge:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Nintendo’s Switch was hacked to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/2/19/17029916/nintendo-switch-hack-linux-fail0verflow">run Linux in February</a>, and
now it’s clear that hackers could go further and run homebrew apps
and games on the device. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2018-switch-hacked-exploit-analysis">Eurogamer reports</a> that two exploits
have been detailed this week that allow hackers to exploit a
hardware flaw in Nvidia’s Tegra X1 (that powers the Switch) and
gain access to the Switch’s operating system. Nintendo cannot
patch the hardware flaw without releasing a new version of the
Switch, which means that at least 14 million devices are
vulnerable.</p>

<p>It’s a jailbreak that’s similar to a “tethered” iPhone jailbreak,
meaning it needs to be performed on every boot via USB. The hack
doesn’t require a modchip, although it’s likely that third parties
will now create Switch hardware mods to assist with the jailbreak.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It&#8217;s not what you want, but I&#8217;m going to say this is not a &#8220;nightmare scenario&#8221; for Nintendo. A nightmare scenario would be something that exposes people to a remote exploit, and this isn&#8217;t that. Nintendo must be pissed at Nvidia though.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Nvidia Tegra Flaw Allows Nintendo Switch to Be Jailbroken’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/25/nintendo-switch-hack">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>How Merchants Use Facebook to Flood Amazon With Fake Reviews</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/how-merchants-secretly-use-facebook-to-flood-amazon-with-fake-reviews/2018/04/23/5dad1e30-4392-11e8-8569-26fda6b404c7_story.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qul" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/facebook-amazon-fake-reviews" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34797</id>
	<published>2018-04-24T22:25:33Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-24T22:25:34Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Elizabeth Dwoskin and Craig Timberg, reporting for The Washington Post:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>On Amazon, customer comments can help a product surge in
popularity. The online retail giant says that more than 99 percent
of its reviews are legitimate because they are written by real
shoppers who aren’t paid for them.</p>

<p>But a Washington Post examination found that for some popular
product categories, such as Bluetooth headphones and speakers, the
vast majority of reviews appear to violate Amazon’s prohibition on
paid reviews. Such reviews have certain characteristics, such as
repetitive wording that people probably cut and paste in.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>What a shitshow. I don&#8217;t understand why Amazon doesn&#8217;t clean this mess up &#8212; it does them no good whatsoever to have all these fraudulent reviews. Same thing with counterfeit products, but they&#8217;ve let that fester too. (<a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2018/04/24/how-merchants-use-facebook-to-flood-amazon-with-fake-reviews/?utm_source=loopinsight.com/twitter&amp;utm_campaign=twitter&amp;utm_medium=referral">Via Dave Mark</a>.)</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘How Merchants Use Facebook to Flood Amazon With Fake Reviews’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/facebook-amazon-fake-reviews">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>The iPad’s Focus Problem</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@lkanies/apple-has-a-focus-problem-8a1acee28b7d" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quk" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/ipad-kanies-focus" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34796</id>
	<published>2018-04-24T21:02:20Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-24T21:38:47Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Luke Kanies:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Unlike touch, keyboards are inherently targeted. While touch is
powerful specifically because of your ability to directly
manipulate the software you’re using, keyboards must first be
pointed at a place that needs text. They need focus. And here’s
where the iPad falls down.</p>

<p>It has no concept of focus. Or rather, it obviously does, but its
designers are in denial about it. Keyboard focus is littered
throughout the platform, from the presence of a cursor when
inputting text, to the software keyboard auto-hiding when no text
field is in use. When you’re producing text, this generally works
pretty well.</p>

<p>But the keyboard is used for far more than typing. Whether it’s
command-tabbing between applications or using shortcuts within
them, the keyboard is a critical control device. And it just does
not work right on the iPad.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/gruber/status/987774563558838272">I tweeted about this same thing</a> over the weekend, while testing out <a href="http://matias.ca/laptoppro/mac/">a new keyboard</a> that Jason Snell <a href="https://twitter.com/jsnell/status/986691168644689920">convinced me to buy</a>. It seems crazy to me the iPad lets you command-tab between full-screen apps, but when you&#8217;re in split screen mode there&#8217;s (a) no way to switch between the apps on screen using the keyboard, and (b) no indication of which app has keyboard focus.</p>

<p>Off the top of my head, I think command-tab switching should include the individual apps in split screen mode.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘The iPad&#8217;s Focus Problem’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/ipad-kanies-focus">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>John Paczkowski on Facebook and Google</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/johnpaczkowski/make-developers-great-again" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quj" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/paczkowski-facebook-google" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34795</id>
	<published>2018-04-24T20:18:29Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-24T20:18:31Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>John Paczkowski, writing for BuzzFeed:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A few weeks from now, Facebook and Google will hold their yearly
developer conferences, massive events meant to celebrate their
platforms and visions for the future. They&#8217;re typically packed
full of grand pronouncements, flashy demos, and Google
Glass-wearing skydivers or CEO-impersonating celebrities. Bands
play. Drinks flow. They are spectacles, intended to ignite
enthusiasm and burnish the Facebook and Google brands. But after a
year in which Facebook and Google played pivotal roles in
spreading misinformation and were exposed as data-greedy growth
goblins, there should be little cause for celebration.</p>

<p>If the platforms are serious about healing themselves, you should
be able to see it in a show that&#8217;s more about fixing what&#8217;s broken
rather than building something new. And if they aren’t serious?
Expect the same shiny, happy-fun wow-fests.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I would bet big money on &#8220;the same shiny, happy-fun wow-fests&#8221;.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘John Paczkowski on Facebook and Google’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/24/paczkowski-facebook-google">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Turn Touch Wooden Smart Home Remote</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://turntouch.com/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qui" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/21/turn-touch" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34794</id>
	<published>2018-04-21T23:13:25Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-21T23:13:26Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>My thanks to Turn Touch for sponsoring this week&#8217;s DF RSS feed to promote their beautiful wooden smart home remote. Ever wanted to control Spotify on your phone without looking at your phone? Do you have smart lights like Philips Hue and want a phone-free way to change scenes and colors? Turn Touch is your answer.</p>

<p>Turn Touch is a wooden smart home remote. Forget plastic, this is a remote as stylish as your home. It controls every smart home device that speaks Wi-Fi. You can also use it to control your Mac and iOS devices over Bluetooth. This includes Keynote, iTunes, Quicktime, Spotify, Sonos, and lots more.</p>

<p>Buy a remote for your home or office for only $59 (with free shipping). It&#8217;s a great gift for friends or yourself.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Turn Touch Wooden Smart Home Remote’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/21/turn-touch">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>iPhone X Customer Satisfaction: Impressively High Across All Features, With One Predictable Exception</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://techpinions.com/top-takeaways-from-studying-iphone-x-owners/52639" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quh" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/iphone-x-customer-satisfaction" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34793</id>
	<published>2018-04-21T01:30:47Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-21T01:41:31Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Ben Bajarin, on the result of a survey of iPhone X owners conducted last month:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When it came to overall customer satisfaction, iPhone X owners in
our study gave the product an overall 97% customer satisfaction.
While that number is impressive, what really stands out when you
do customer satisfaction studies is the percentage who say they
are very satisfied with the product. Considering you add up the
total number of <em>very satisfied</em>, and <em>satisfied</em>, to get your
total customer satisfaction number a product can have a high
number of satisfied responses and lower number of very satisfied
responses and still achieve a high number. The higher the very
satisfied responses, the better a product truly is. <em>In our study,
85% of iPhone X owners said they were very satisfied with the
product.</em></p>

<p>That number is amongst the highest I’ve seen in all the customer
satisfaction studied we have conducted across a range of
technology products. Just to contrast that with the <a href="http://techpinions.com/the-state-of-apple-watch-satisfaction/41126">original
Apple Watch research with Wristly I was involved in</a>, 66% of
Apple Watch owners indicated they were very satisfied with Apple
Watch, a product which also ranked a 97% customer satisfaction
number in the first Apple Watch study we did.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Wait until you see the feature-by-feature results.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘iPhone X Customer Satisfaction: Impressively High Across All Features, With One Predictable Exception’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/iphone-x-customer-satisfaction">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Google Gives Up on Allo, Backs Unencrypted Successor to SMS</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/19/17252486/google-android-messages-chat-rcs-anil-sabharwal-imessage-texting" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qug" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/google-rcs" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34792</id>
	<published>2018-04-21T01:07:26Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-21T03:23:52Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Dieter Bohn, writing for The Verge:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Instead of bringing a better app to the table, it’s trying to
change the rules of the texting game, on a global scale. Google
has been quietly corralling every major cellphone carrier on the
planet into adopting technology to replace SMS. It’s going to be
called “Chat,” and it’s based on a standard called the “Universal
Profile for Rich Communication Services.” SMS is the default that
everybody has to fall back to, and so Google’s goal is to make
that default texting experience on an Android phone as good as
other modern messaging apps.</p>

<p>As part of that effort, Google says it’s “pausing” work on its
most recent entry into the messaging space, Allo. It’s the sort of
“pause” that involves transferring almost the entire team off the
project and putting all its resources into another app, Android
Messages. [&#8230;]</p>

<p>But remember, Chat is a carrier-based service, not a Google
service. It’s just “Chat,” not “Google Chat.” In a sign of its
strategic importance to Google, the company has spearheaded
development on the new standard, so that every carrier’s Chat
services will be interoperable. But, like SMS, Chat won’t be
end-to-end encrypted, and it will follow the same legal
intercept standards. In other words: it won’t be as secure as
iMessage or Signal.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It is unconscionable for Google to back a new protocol that isn&#8217;t end-to-end encrypted. End-to-end encryption is table stakes for any new communication platform today. Apple should ignore this &#8212; if it&#8217;s not secure it should be a non-starter.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/waltmossberg/status/987190616877608960">Walt Mossberg</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Bottom line: Google builds an insecure messaging system controlled
by carriers who are in bed with governments everywhere at exactly
the time when world publics are more worried about data collection
and theft than ever.</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Google Gives Up on Allo, Backs Unencrypted Successor to SMS’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/google-rcs">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Susan Kare to Be Awarded AIGA Medal</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-woman-who-gave-the-macintosh-a-smile" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quf" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/kare-aiga" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34791</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T22:10:51Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T22:49:56Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Alexandra Lange, writing for The New Yorker:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Kare, who is sixty-four, <a href="https://www.aiga.org/medalist-susan-kare">will be honored for her work</a> on
April 20th, by her fellow designers, with the prestigious AIGA
medal. In 1982, she was a sculptor and sometime curator when her
high-school friend Andy Hertzfeld asked her to create graphics for
a new computer that he was working on in California. Kare brought
<a href="https://www.moma.org/collection/works/188382?artist_id=38483&amp;locale=en&amp;page=1&amp;sov_referrer=artist">a Grid notebook</a> to her job interview at Apple Computer. On
its pages, she had sketched, in pink marker, a series of icons to
represent the commands that Hertzfeld’s software would execute.
Each square represented a pixel. A pointing finger meant “Paste.”
A paintbrush symbolized “MacPaint.” Scissors said “Cut.” Kare told
me about this origin moment: “As soon as I started work, Andy
Hertzfeld wrote an icon editor and font editor so I could design
images and letterforms using the Mac, not paper,” she said. “But I
loved the puzzle-like nature of working in 16&#8201;&#215;&#8201;16 and 32&#8201;&#215;&#8201;32
pixel icon grids, and the marriage of craft and metaphor.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Susan Kare deserves every award in the world. Her work was central &#8212; essential &#8212; to what made the Macintosh the Macintosh. The early Macintosh was not just the most endearing computer ever made, I&#8217;d argue that it remains the most endearing computer ever made &#8212; and in large part that was due to Susan Kare&#8217;s icons and fonts.</p>

<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/151277875">My interview with Kare at the Layers conference in 2016</a> is one of the highlights of my career.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Susan Kare to Be Awarded AIGA Medal’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/kare-aiga">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>SmugMug Acquires Flickr</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2018/04/20/smugmug-buys-flickr-verizon-oath/537377002/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/que" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/smugmug-flickr" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34790</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T21:43:57Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T21:43:59Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Jessica Guynn, reporting for USA Today</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Flickr has been snapped up by Silicon Valley photo-sharing and
storage company SmugMug, USA Today has learned.</p>

<p>SmugMug CEO Don MacAskill told USA Today he&#8217;s committed to
breathing new life into the faded social networking pioneer,
which hosted photos and lively interactions long before it
became trendy.</p>

<p>SmugMug, an independent, family-run company, will maintain Flickr
as a standalone community of amateur and professional
photographers and give the long neglected service the focus and
resources it deserves, MacAskill said in an exclusive interview.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I hope it works. Flickr was so great back in the day. But I fear it&#8217;s too late, and the world has moved on.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘SmugMug Acquires Flickr’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/smugmug-flickr">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Regarding Linus Sebastian’s Damaged iMac Pro Saga</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.macrumors.com/2018/04/18/linus-tech-tips-imac-pro-repair-video/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qud" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/sebastian-imac-pro" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34789</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T20:56:39Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T21:58:49Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Joe Rossignol has an excellent piece at MacRumors on the saga of Linus Sebastian&#8217;s iMac Pro that Apple has declined to repair:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>After the repair was declined by Apple, Sebastian and his team
contacted an Apple Authorized Service Provider in Canada, where
they are located. The repair shop also declined the repair, but
their reason was allegedly that Apple has yet to offer the
required certification courses to service the iMac Pro.</p>

<p>However, Apple&#8217;s internal iMac Pro Service Readiness Guide
obtained by MacRumors states that <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT206048">ATLAS online training and
learning resources</a> for servicing the iMac Pro have been
available in English since December. We also spoke to multiple
sources who completed the course and received certification
months ago.</p>

<p>The guide adds that iMac Pro service parts availability began in
early to mid January, with replacement logic boards, flash
storage, and memory available by late February. Multiple sources
at Apple Authorized Service Providers also confirmed that iMac Pro
displays are available with two-week-or-less delivery estimates.</p>

<p>MacRumors contacted a reliable source who confirmed that Apple
Authorized Service Providers are permitted to deny service for any
product that has been opened or modified by a customer, regardless
of warranty, both for safety reasons and to avoid responsibility
if the machine cannot be fixed.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sebastian&#8217;s video about his saga is deeply disingenuous &#8212; he makes it sound as though Apple isn&#8217;t able to repair any iMac Pro with a damaged display. As Rossignol&#8217;s reporting makes clear, that&#8217;s not true. On the surface it does sound wrong that Apple refuses to repair Sebastian&#8217;s iMac Pro, even though he&#8217;s willing to pay for it. But in car terms, Apple is saying his iMac is totaled. Apple &#8212; or at least the technicians and Genius Bar staffers who&#8217;ve looked at it &#8212; want no part of this machine, for legitimate reasons.</p>

<p><strong>See also:</strong> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aF6l2ydXtW4">Rene Ritchie&#8217;s video on the saga</a>.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Regarding Linus Sebastian&#8217;s Damaged iMac Pro Saga’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/sebastian-imac-pro">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Daisy, Apple’s iPhone Disassembling Robot Successor to Liam</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/04/apple-adds-earth-day-donations-to-trade-in-and-recycling-program/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/quc" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/daisy" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34788</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T20:35:46Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T21:32:44Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Among Apple&#8217;s Earth Day-related announcements:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple’s newest disassembly robot, Daisy, is the most efficient way
to reclaim more of the valuable materials stored in iPhone.
Created through years of R&amp;D, Daisy incorporates revolutionary
technology based on Apple’s learnings from Liam, its first
disassembly robot launched in 2016. Daisy is made from some of
Liam’s parts and is capable of disassembling nine versions of
iPhone and sorting their high-quality components for recycling.
Daisy can take apart up to 200 iPhone devices per hour, removing
and sorting components, so that Apple can recover materials that
traditional recyclers can’t &#8212; and at a higher quality.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s just my <em>2001</em> obsession, but I think it&#8217;s a solid bet that Daisy is named after the song HAL sings while Bowman is disconnecting him.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Daisy, Apple&#8217;s iPhone Disassembling Robot Successor to Liam’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/daisy">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Apple GiveBack</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.apple.com/shop/trade-in" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qub" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/apple-giveback" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34787</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T20:31:54Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T21:47:56Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>New recycling program from Apple:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Trade in your eligible device for an Apple Store Gift Card. If
it’s not eligible for credit, we’ll recycle it for free. No matter
the model or condition, we can turn it into something good for you
and good for the planet.</p>

<p>And through April 30, we’ll make a donation to Conservation
International for every device we receive &#8212; getting us even
closer to leaving the world better than we found it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I tried my space black first-generation Apple Watch &#8212; which I paid $1,100 for in 2015 &#8212; and Apple is offering me $75. I suspect I could sell it for more than that. It&#8217;s fully functional and the display and case are in near-mint condition, thanks to the scratch resistance of sapphire and DLC-coated stainless steel. Perhaps this is obvious, but this GiveBack program seems intended for devices that are no longer useful. I&#8217;d find it interesting if Apple had one unified program for trading in old devices, both still useful (which Apple could sell as refurbished) and not (which would be recycled).</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple GiveBack’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/apple-giveback">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Jackass of the Week: Analyst Neil Campling</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/20/apple-iphone-x-discontinued-this-year-analyst-says.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qua" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/campling-jackass" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34786</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T19:49:32Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T21:28:30Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Arjun Kharpal, writing for CNBC under the jacktastic headline &#8220;Apple&#8217;s iPhone X Will Be Killed Off This Year, Analyst Says&#8221;:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>TSMC&#8217;s record inventory levels are due to Apple not buying
components for any future iPhone X models, suggesting the device
will be killed off this year, Campling said.</p>

<p>&#8220;With the declines in iPhone X orders and the inventory issue at
TSMC at record highs, which basically reflect a need to burn off
inventory. Why? Because the iPhone X is dead,&#8221; Campling wrote in
his note.</p>

<p>&#8220;The simple problem with X is that it is too expensive,&#8221; Campling
told CNBC by phone on Friday, talking about the device&#8217;s $999
price tag. &#8220;Consumers are turning their backs on high-priced
smartphones.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It might be true that the iPhone X will be discontinued in September when new iPhones are announced, but I guarantee it will be replaced by a successor. It actually makes sense that Apple wouldn&#8217;t keep the iPhone X around for another year at a lower price &#8212; that&#8217;s the iPhone 8&#8217;s role.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t know why CNBC is paying credence to Campling on this, because by all accounts the iPhone X is selling well or very well. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/01/cnbc-transcript-apple-ceo-tim-cook-speaks-with-cnbc.html">Tim Cook told CNBC in February</a> that &#8220;iPhone X was our most popular iPhone, despite not beginning to ship until November.&#8221; <a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/iphone-x-alone-generated-35-total-handset-industry-profits-q4-2017/">A report this week from Counterpoint</a> claims the iPhone X alone accounted for 35 percent of all profits in the industry in Q4 2017 &#8212; even though it only went on sale in November. (The iPhone 8 and 8 Plus combined for 34 percent; all iPhones combined accounted for 86 percent. I don&#8217;t know how much credence to give to Counterpoint&#8217;s report because I don&#8217;t know their methodology, but if their numbers are even vaguely accurate, Apple has almost no competition in the premium handset market. Samsung&#8217;s top two phones combined account for less than 5 percent of industry profits, and no other company had a phone that cracked the top 10.)</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Jackass of the Week: Analyst Neil Campling’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/campling-jackass">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>‘2001: A Space Odyssey’: What It Means, and How It Was Made</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/04/23/2001-a-space-odyssey-what-it-means-and-how-it-was-made" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu9" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/2001-chiasson" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34785</id>
	<published>2018-04-20T19:24:05Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-20T19:59:33Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Nice piece by Dan Chiasson for The New Yorker &#8220;on the tedium and the triumph of <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em>&#8221;:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Kubrick brought to his vision of the future the studiousness you
would expect from a history film. <em>2001</em> is, in part, a fastidious
period piece about a period that had yet to happen. Kubrick had
seen exhibits at the 1964 World’s Fair, and pored over a magazine
article titled “Home of the Future.” The lead production designer
on the film, Tony Masters, noticed that the world of <em>2001</em>
eventually became a distinct time and place, with the kind of
coherent aesthetic that would merit a sweeping historical label,
like “Georgian” or “Victorian.” “We designed a way to live,” he
recalled, “down to the last knife and fork.” (The Arne Jacobsen
flatware, designed in 1957, was made famous by its use in the
film, and is still in production.) By rendering a not-too-distant
future, Kubrick set himself up for a test: thirty-three years
later, his audiences would still be around to grade his
predictions. Part of his genius was that he understood how to rig
the results. Many elements from his set designs were contributions
from major brands &#8212; Whirlpool, Macy’s, DuPont, Parker Pens, Nikon
&#8212; which quickly cashed in on their big-screen exposure. If 2001
the year looked like <em>2001</em> the movie, it was partly because the
film’s imaginary design trends were made real.</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘&#8216;2001: A Space Odyssey&#8217;: What It Means, and How It Was Made’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/20/2001-chiasson">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>CNN: YouTube Ran Ads From Hundreds of Mainstream Brands on Extremist Channels</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://money.cnn.com/2018/04/19/technology/youtube-ads-extreme-content-investigation/index.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu8" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/youtube-cnn" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34784</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T23:43:15Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T23:43:16Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Paul P. Murphy, Kaya Yurieff, and Gianluca Mezzofiore, reporting for CNN:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Ads from over 300 companies and organizations &#8212; including tech
giants, major retailers, newspapers and government agencies &#8212; ran
on YouTube channels promoting white nationalists, Nazis,
pedophilia, conspiracy theories and North Korean propaganda, a CNN
investigation has found.</p>

<p>Companies such as Adidas, Amazon, Cisco, Facebook, Hershey,
Hilton, LinkedIn, Mozilla, Netflix, Nordstrom and Under Armour may
have unknowingly helped finance some of these channels via the
advertisements they paid for on Google-owned YouTube.</p>

<p>US tax dollars may have gone to the channels, too. Ads from five
US government agencies, such as the Department of Transportation
and Centers for Disease Control, appeared on the channels.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Facebook is getting a lot of attention lately, but it&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/jkottke/status/986638108119707659">starting to feel like YouTube is losing its credibility</a> too.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘CNN: YouTube Ran Ads From Hundreds of Mainstream Brands on Extremist Channels’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/youtube-cnn">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Amazon and Best Buy Team Up to Sell Smart TVs</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/retail-rivals-amazon-and-best-buy-team-up-to-sell-smart-tvs-1524045603" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu7" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/amazon-best-buy-fire-tv" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34783</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T22:41:04Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T22:41:05Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>David Pierce:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Rivals Amazon.com Inc. and Best Buy Co. are joining forces to sell
television sets powered by Amazon’s Fire TV operating system.</p>

<p>Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos and Best Buy CEO Hubert Joly revealed the
partnership on Tuesday at a Best Buy store in Bellevue, Wash. The
companies will sell 11 models, starting this summer with TVs by
Toshiba and Best Buy house brand Insignia. Best Buy will feature
the Amazon-powered TVs in its stores and on its website and become
the exclusive merchant of these TVs on Amazon.com.</p>

<p>“What we’re doing is so deeply integrated,” Mr. Bezos said,
acknowledging the fact that his company and Best Buy are
often considered rivals. “It’s only possible because we trust
each other.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I don&#8217;t know if Best Buy should trust Amazon or not, but I do know I wish Apple would get it together and make some TVs with Apple TV built-in.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Amazon and Best Buy Team Up to Sell Smart TVs’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/amazon-best-buy-fire-tv">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Pew: Majority of U.S. Teens Worry About School Shootings</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/04/18/a-majority-of-u-s-teens-fear-a-shooting-could-happen-at-their-school-and-most-parents-share-their-concern/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu6" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/pew-us-teens-worried-about-shootings" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34782</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T20:51:44Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T21:22:18Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Nikki Graf, writing for Pew Research Center:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the aftermath of the deadly shooting at a high school in
Parkland, Florida, a majority of American teens say they are very
or somewhat worried about the possibility of a shooting happening
at their school &#8212; and most parents of teens share that concern,
according to new Pew Research Center surveys of teens ages 13 to
17 and parents with children in the same age range.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, when it comes to what can be done to prevent this kind
of violence, far more teens view proposals focused on mental
illness, assault-style weapon bans and the use of metal detectors
in schools as potentially effective than say the same about
allowing teachers and school officials to carry guns in schools.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It is absolutely shameful that we as a country have let it get to the point where a majority of teenagers are worried about a shooting at their school. When I was in high school 30 years ago, the notion that there even could be a shooting at my school never  crossed my mind.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Pew: Majority of U.S. Teens Worry About School Shootings’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/pew-us-teens-worried-about-shootings">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Barack Obama on the Parkland Students</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://time.com/collection/most-influential-people-2018/5217568/parkland-students/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu4" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/obama-parkland" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34780</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T20:37:55Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T20:37:56Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Barack Obama, writing for Time magazine&#8217;s &#8220;Most Influential People of 2018&#8221; on Parkland, Florida students Cameron Kasky, Jaclyn Corin, David Hogg, Emma González, and Alex Wind:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>America’s response to mass shootings has long followed a
predictable pattern. We mourn. Offer thoughts and prayers.
Speculate about the motives. And then &#8212; even as no developed
country endures a homicide rate like ours, a difference explained
largely by pervasive accessibility to guns; even as the majority
of gun owners support commonsense reforms &#8212; the political debate
spirals into acrimony and paralysis.</p>

<p>This time, something different is happening. This time, our
children are calling us to account.</p>

<p>The Parkland, Fla., students don’t have the kind of lobbyists or
big budgets for attack ads that their opponents do. Most of them
can’t even vote yet.</p>

<p>But they have the power so often inherent in youth: to see the
world anew; to reject the old constraints, outdated conventions
and cowardice too often dressed up as wisdom.</p>

<p>The power to insist that America can be better.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He has such a distinct writing style &#8212; I can hear his voice as I read his words.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Barack Obama on the Parkland Students’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/obama-parkland">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>A Flaw-by-Flaw Guide to Facebook’s New GDPR Privacy Changes</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/17/facebook-gdpr-changes/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu3" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/facebook-gdpr-constine" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34779</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T19:14:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T19:14:04Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Josh Constine, writing for TechCrunch:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Facebook is about to start pushing European users to speed through
giving consent for its new GDPR privacy law compliance changes. It
will ask people to review how Facebook applies data from the web
to target them with ads, and surface the sensitive profile info
they share. Facebook will also allow European and Canadian users
to turn on facial recognition after six years of the feature being
blocked there. But with a design that encourages rapidly hitting
the “Agree” button, a lack of granular controls, a laughably
cheatable parental consent request for teens and an aesthetic
overhaul of Download Your Information that doesn’t make it any
easier to switch social networks, Facebook shows it’s still hungry
for your data.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>A good example of the dark patterns they&#8217;re employing:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>But the fact that the button to reject the new Terms of Service
isn’t even a button, it’s a tiny “see your options” hyperlink,
shows how badly Facebook wants to avoid you closing your account.
When Facebook’s product designer for the GDPR flow was asked if
she thought this hyperlink was the best way to present the
alternative to the big “I Accept” button, she disingenuously said
yes, eliciting scoffs from the room of reporters. It seems obvious
that Facebook is trying to minimize the visibility of the path to
account deletion rather than making it an obvious course of action
if you don’t agree to its terms.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Not only is it a tiny hyperlink instead of a button, the link is just a few pixels above the big &#8220;I ACCEPT&#8221; button.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘A Flaw-by-Flaw Guide to Facebook’s New GDPR Privacy Changes’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/facebook-gdpr-constine">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>How Jason Snell Writes on iPad</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2018/04/writing-on-my-ipad-at-home/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu2" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/snell-ipad-writing" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34778</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T18:27:09Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T18:27:10Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/gruber/status/986643399594962944">I asked</a>, Jason answered:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A reader on Twitter suggested I buy <a href="https://amzn.to/2vqgAC1">this iPad stand on
Amazon</a>, and I’ve been using it ever since. It’s surprisingly
sturdy. The base that approximates the foot of an iMac is metal,
not plastic. A hinge lets me pivot the iPad up and down and
likewise doesn’t feel cheap. And the clip mechanism &#8212; the stand
comes with clips for large and small iPads &#8212; is strong enough to
hold my iPad without any worry of it sliding out. Best of all, the
thing rotates, so I can use my iPad in portrait (for more words on
the screen) or landscape (for use with Split View) as I see fit.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The stand is only $40, so I ordered one yesterday. I also ordered a <a href="http://matias.ca/laptoppro/mac/">Matias Laptop Pro</a>, a Bluetooth mechanical keyboard that Snell &#8212; who&#8217;s in even deeper than I am with a mechanical keyboard collection &#8212; says feels and sounds <a href="https://twitter.com/jsnell/status/986691168644689920">quite a bit like an Apple Extended Keyboard II</a>.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘How Jason Snell Writes on iPad’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/snell-ipad-writing">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Reuters: Facebook to Put 1.5 Billion Users Out of Reach of New EU Privacy Law</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-privacy-eu-exclusive/exclusive-facebook-to-put-1-5-billion-users-out-of-reach-of-new-eu-privacy-law-idUSKBN1HQ00P" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu1" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/facebook-gdpr-ireland" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34777</id>
	<published>2018-04-19T18:16:15Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-19T18:16:17Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>David Ingram, reporting for Reuters:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If a new European law restricting what companies can do with
people’s online data went into effect tomorrow, almost 1.9 billion
Facebook Inc users around the world would be protected by it. The
online social network is making changes that ensure the number
will be much smaller.</p>

<p>Facebook members outside the United States and Canada, whether
they know it or not, are currently governed by terms of service
agreed with the company’s international headquarters in Ireland.</p>

<p>Next month, Facebook is planning to make that the case for only
European users, meaning 1.5 billion members in Africa, Asia,
Australia and Latin America will not fall under the European
Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which takes
effect on May 25.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This sounds like bullshit to me, if they plan to continue funneling the revenue they generate from those users through their Irish subsidiary.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Reuters: Facebook to Put 1.5 Billion Users Out of Reach of New EU Privacy Law’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/19/facebook-gdpr-ireland">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://turntouch.com/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qu5" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2018/04/turn_touch_wooden_smart_home_r" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/feeds/sponsors//11.34781</id>
	<author><name>Daring Fireball Department of Commerce</name></author>
	<published>2018-04-19T16:52:00-04:00</published>
	<updated>2018-04-21T19:13:32-04:00</updated>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Ever wanted to control Spotify on your phone without looking at your phone? Do you have smart lights like Philips Hue and want a phone-free way to change scenes and colors? Turn Touch is your answer.</p>

<p>Turn Touch is a wooden smart home remote. Forget plastic, this is a remote as stylish as your home. It controls every smart home device that speaks Wi-Fi. Also use it to control your Mac and iOS devices over Bluetooth. This includes Keynote, iTunes, Quicktime, Spotify, Sonos, and lots more.</p>

<p>Buy a remote for your home or office for only $59 (with free shipping). A great gift for friends or yourself.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Turn Touch Wooden Smart Home Remote’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2018/04/turn_touch_wooden_smart_home_r">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
	<title>[Sponsor] Turn Touch Wooden Smart Home Remote</title></entry><entry>
	<title>Daring Fireball Sponsorship Openings</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtx" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/df-sponsorship-openings" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34773</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T22:00:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T22:04:27Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>The next few weeks &#8212; including this current one &#8212; are open on the DF sponsorship calendar. Get in touch if you have a product or service to promote to DF&#8217;s savvy audience.</p>

<p>The display ads &#8212; where it says &#8220;Your Ad Here&#8221; over there on the left &#8212; have openings too. If you jump on this week&#8217;s opening or next week&#8217;s, I&#8217;ll throw in the display ad for the remainder of April as a bonus.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Daring Fireball Sponsorship Openings’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/df-sponsorship-openings">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Jeff Bezos Releases Non-Bezos Number: 100 Million Prime Subscribers</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1018724/000119312518121161/d456916dex991.htm" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qu0" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/bezos-100m-prime-subscribers" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34776</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T21:49:51Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T21:49:53Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Jeff Bezos, in his annual Amazon shareholder letter:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>13 years post-launch, we have exceeded 100 million paid Prime
members globally. In 2017 Amazon shipped more than five billion
items with Prime worldwide, and more new members joined Prime than
in any previous year &#8212; both worldwide and in the U.S. Members in
the U.S. now receive unlimited free two-day shipping on over 100
million different items.</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Jeff Bezos Releases Non-Bezos Number: 100 Million Prime Subscribers’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/bezos-100m-prime-subscribers">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>The Menu Bar</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://wormsandviruses.com/2018/03/the-menu-bar/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtz" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/wellborn-menu-bar" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34775</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T20:14:05Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T20:21:08Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Jack Wellborn:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The menu bar has been, and in my opinion remains, the best
mechanism for providing familiarity, discoverability, and
progressive disclosure in user interfaces on any platform. Even
beyond the Mac, anyone who has clicked on a File menu in one
platform has a pretty good shot at guessing where a Save command
might be when provided a File menu somewhere else. Likewise and
also regardless of operating system, someone presented with an
entirely new application can safely open and explore menus to try
and locate features they might need. Never pivoted data before,
but need to for the first time? Hey look, there’s a menu in the
bar called Data! Finally, let’s say that same seemingly one-time
operation becomes a regular course of action that is needed
multiple times a day. The best menu bars provide an equivalent
keyboard shortcut right next to the command so, for example,
anyone can discover how to save using command &#8212; s without having
to be told.</p>

<p>So then why are menu bars fading out of more modern UX
conventions?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Such a great piece. The menu bar, in my opinion, is the single biggest reason why Mac apps can grow to a greater manageable complexity than iOS apps. I&#8217;m not saying iOS should get a menu bar &#8212; I&#8217;m saying this is why it makes sense for Apple to maintain its dual platform strategy. The Mac&#8217;s menu bar &#8212; and the many dozens of commands it allows an app to offer in an organized, out-of-your-way-until-you-want-to-see-it system-wide standard interface &#8212; epitomizes my argument from when the iPad first shipped: <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2010/12/future_of_the_mac_in_an_ios_world">It’s the heaviness of the Mac that allows iOS to remain light.</a></p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Menu Bar’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/wellborn-menu-bar">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>A Tale of Two QuickTimes</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2018/04/a-tale-of-two-quicktimes/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qty" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/two-quicktimes" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34774</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T16:57:44Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T20:10:33Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Dan Moren, writing for Six Colors:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Among the casualties of the impending transition to 64-bit apps is
one long-lasting oddity: QuickTime 7 Pro.</p>

<p>What makes this app so unusual are a few factors. For one thing,
it’s one of Apple’s own apps. For another, it was first released
in 2005, making it almost 13 years old, though it hasn’t seen an
update in about 8 years.</p>

<p>But despite its age and the fact that the writing was on the wall
for QuickTime 7, news that it wouldn’t see an update when macOS
makes the jump to all-64-bit-all-the-time sparked some cries of
frustration from users, including both myself and Jason, who have
carved out a place in their workflows &#8212; and their hearts &#8212; for
this little anachronism.</p>

<p>The biggest reason that people are up in arms about the death of
QuickTime 7 Pro is that its successor, QuickTime Player X, never
quite filled its shoes when it came to features.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I still use QuickTime 7 Pro, too &#8212; I have it set as my default app to open any video file. When I <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208436">checked my list of installed apps looking for any remaining 32-bit hold-outs</a>, none of the apps I use regularly are 32-bit. But I spotted several irregularly used apps that are.</p>

<p>This was not the case with iOS&#8217;s deprecation of 32-bit apps. With iOS, the only apps I lost use of were a few old games (including <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2011/11/17/apple-removes-texas-holdem-its-only-ios-game-from-app-store/">Apple&#8217;s own Texas Hold ’Em game</a>, which was really rather fun). With the Mac, I&#8217;ll be losing a few useful apps. But that was true of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple%27s_transition_to_Intel_processors">PowerPC to Intel transition</a>, and the <a href="http://www.storiesofapple.net/the-68k-ppc-transition-and-snow-leopard-comparing-apples-to-oranges.html">Motorola 68K to PowerPC transition</a>. I vaguely recall some software that ran under System 6 but broke under System 7 in 1991. This is the price we pay for a platform that remains both relevant and (at least compared to Windows) low-cruft.</p>

<p>What makes QuickTime 7 Pro particularly irksome, as Moren points out, is that it&#8217;s Apple&#8217;s own software and Apple has resolutely refused to address QuickTime X&#8217;s deficiencies for over a decade, so nobody expects to <em>ever</em> see a full replacement for QuickTime Pro. Maybe there&#8217;s an opportunity here for a third-party app to take up the mantle &#8212; but if that hasn&#8217;t happened in the last decade, I&#8217;m not too hopeful about it happening now.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘A Tale of Two QuickTimes’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/18/two-quicktimes">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/design_plagiarism" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qtv" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34771</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T01:00:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T01:08:09Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">There’s a difference between copying an idea and copying an implementation of that idea.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>In response to <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/on_normalizing_ripoffs">my piece earlier today on normalizing design rip-offs</a>, a few readers who object to my statement that every company does <em>not</em> copy from everyone else pointed me to this 2015 piece by Ron Amadeo for Ars Technica, &#8220;<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/06/everybody-copies-everyone-ios-9-features-inspired-by-android/">Everybody Copies Everyone: iOS 9 Features Inspired by Android</a>&#8221;:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple announced iOS 9 on Monday, and while watching the keynote, I
had just a little bit of déjà vu. Most of iOS 9&#8217;s new features
seem to be squarely aimed at Apple&#8217;s biggest rival in mobile:
Android. Specifically, they were about catching up to Android.</p>

<p>Search improvements, proactive assistance, split screen, and
transit directions? It&#8217;s been done, but the differences are the
fun part, so we chased down the new iOS 9 screenshots and compared
them to their Android counterparts. It&#8217;s not just about who copied
whom; it&#8217;s also a chance to look at the different designs of the
two operating systems. And hey, Apple isn&#8217;t the only one taking
ideas from a competitor. Android M&#8217;s selectable app permissions
are an exact copy of the iOS model.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is not copying. Following? Sure. That&#8217;s how competition works. I&#8217;m not arguing that if Company A implements a certain feature first, that no other company can ever implement that feature without ripping off Company A. Look at the side-by-side screenshots in Amadeo&#8217;s article. Were all these features on Android first? Sure. Do any of these screenshots leave even one iota of confusion regarding which is iOS and which is Android? No. If you don&#8217;t see the difference between these examples and <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2018/04/huawei-stage-lighting.jpg">what Huawei did with their Portrait mode feature</a>, I don&#8217;t know what to say. There&#8217;s a difference between copying an idea and copying an implementation of that idea.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s why I like the phrase &#8220;design plagiarism&#8221;. Maybe you think Amadeo&#8217;s examples do constitute &#8220;copying&#8221;. But they&#8217;re not plagiarism. If you write an article, and then I write my own article about the same topic, that just means you were first. But if I copy your article and just change a few words, that&#8217;s plagiarism. There&#8217;s a big difference.<sup id="fnr1-2018-04-17"><a href="#fn1-2018-04-17">1</a></sup></p>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1-2018-04-17">
<p>This, by the way, is why I&#8217;ve always felt Apple&#8217;s misguided &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Computer,_Inc._v._Microsoft_Corp.">look-and-feel&#8221; lawsuit against Microsoft</a> in the mid-90&#8217;s was a huge mistake from the outset. Windows was clearly not a rip-off or copy of the Mac. There was no confusion which was which, and the Mac was elegant and Windows &#8212; especially pre-Windows 95 &#8212; was simply gross. Have you ever seen screenshots of <a href="https://guidebookgallery.org/screenshots/win101">Windows 1</a> <a href="https://guidebookgallery.org/screenshots/win203">or 2</a>? They&#8217;re so startlingly ugly it&#8217;s hard to believe they&#8217;re real. Even <a href="https://guidebookgallery.org/screenshots/win31">Windows 3</a>, the first version that became popular, was seriously ugly. Apple wasn&#8217;t trying to prevent Microsoft from <em>copying</em> the Mac &#8212; they were trying to prevent Microsoft from using the basic idea of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WIMP_(computing)">windows / icons / mouse pointer</a> GUI. As I wrote about this years ago, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2010/03/regarding_old_apple_microsoft_suit">good ideas are meant to spread</a>.&nbsp;<a href="#fnr1-2018-04-17"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">&#x21A9;&#xFE0E;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ Design Plagiarism</title></entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/on_normalizing_ripoffs" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qts" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34768</id>
	<published>2018-04-18T00:00:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T01:07:43Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">Everyone does not do it, and the companies who do original design work are not ripped off in equal measure.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/28/17165828/huawei-free-buds-truly-wireless-earbuds-hands-on">Vlad Savov, a few weeks ago at The Verge</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I know I’m supposed to be outraged about tech companies blatantly
copying each other’s designs, but I don’t have the naivety for it
anymore. Huawei, the company that’s been shipping copycat Apple
EarPods with its Android smartphones for years, has decided to
also clone Apple’s wireless AirPods, and the product of that is
called <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/27/17167890/huawei-p20-launch-freebuds-wireless-earphones-price">the Huawei FreeBuds</a>. I got my hands on the FreeBuds at
Huawei’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/27/17165822/huawei-p20-pro-specs-price-release-date">P20 launch event</a>, and I found myself pleasantly
surprised by their styling and comfort. Yes, Huawei is copying
Apple; but I’m not a patent lawyer, I just want to see good tech
proliferate, and the FreeBuds look promising.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I have so many problems with this. First, it&#8217;s not &#8220;tech companies blatantly copying each other’s designs&#8221; in the abstract. That phrasing makes it sound like everyone copies from everyone. What&#8217;s going on, and which Huawei exemplifies, is that device makers from China <a href="http://samsungcopiesapple.tumblr.com/">and Korea</a> blatantly copy hardware and software from one company: Apple.</p>

<p>In this case Savov was writing about Huawei&#8217;s copycat wireless earbuds. But the most telling example &#8212; which Savov himself <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/4/17077458/iphone-design-clones-mwc-2018">has documented better than anyone else</a> &#8212; is the iPhone X notch. The notch is unquestionably the <em>worst</em> thing about the iPhone X design &#8212; it is a worthwhile compromise, but <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2017/09/iphone_x_event_thoughts_and_observations#iphone-x">a severe and glaring one</a>. But it lends the iPhone X a distinctive look and <em>can</em> be easily copied, and so of course these companies are shamelessly copying it. Anything they can copy from a successful Apple product, they do. (How many PC laptops look like MacBooks?)</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a software example, from the same Huawei launch event last month: <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2018/04/huawei-stage-lighting.jpg">their camera app&#8217;s Portrait mode with a &#8220;Stage Lighting&#8221; effect</a>. Huawei didn&#8217;t just copy the feature &#8212; they copied Apple&#8217;s UI almost to a T. (Apple uses a 3D wireframe cube to indicate the currently selected lighting effect; Huawei uses a 3D wireframe sphere.) This is design plagiarism.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t think <em>outrage</em> is the right term for how the media should react to such rip-offs. I suggest a mix of contempt and mockery. But they certainly shouldn&#8217;t be pooh-poohed with an &#8220;<em>Eh, everyone does it</em>&#8221; attitude. Everyone does <em>not</em> do it, and the companies who do original design work are not each ripped off in equal measure.</p>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ On Normalizing Rip-Offs</title></entry><entry>
	<title>Elon Musk Memo on the State of Tesla</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://electrek.co/2018/04/17/tesla-model-3-production-goal-6000-units-per-week/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtw" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/17/musk-tesla" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34772</id>
	<published>2018-04-17T22:48:22Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-18T21:39:07Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Skip the Electrek summary and scroll down to the memo itself. It&#8217;s a cogent and fascinating read:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Most of the design tolerances of the Model 3 are already better
than any other car in the world. Soon, they will all be better.
This is not enough. We will keep going until the Model 3 build
precision is a factor of ten better than any other car in the
world. I am not kidding.</p>

<p>Our car needs to be designed and built with such accuracy and
precision that, if an owner measures dimensions, panel gaps and
flushness, and their measurements don’t match the Model 3 specs,
it just means that their measuring tape is wrong.</p>

<p>Some parts suppliers will be unwilling or unable to achieve this
level of precision. I understand that this will be considered an
unreasonable request by some. That’s ok, there are lots of other
car companies with much lower standards. They just can’t work
with Tesla.</p>
</blockquote>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Elon Musk Memo on the State of Tesla’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/17/musk-tesla">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>The Guardian: ‘Far More Than 87 Million Facebook Users Had Data Compromised by Cambridge Analytica’</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/apr/17/facebook-users-data-compromised-far-more-than-87m-mps-told-cambridge-analytica" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtt" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/17/far-more-than-87m" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34769</id>
	<published>2018-04-17T21:50:06Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-17T21:50:07Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Alex Hern, reporting for The Guardian:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Far more than 87 million people may have had their Facebook data
harvested by Cambridge Analytica, according to evidence from
former employee Brittany Kaiser.</p>

<p>Speaking to the Commons digital, culture, media and sport select
committee, Kaiser said Cambridge Analytica had a suite of
personality quizzes designed to extract personal data from the
social network, of which Aleksandr Kogan’s This Is Your Digital
Life app was just one example.</p>

<p>In evidence to the committee, Kaiser wrote: “The Kogan/GSR
datasets and questionnaires were not the only Facebook-connected
questionnaires and datasets which Cambridge Analytica used. I am
aware in a general sense of a wide range of surveys which were
done by CA or its partners, usually with a Facebook login &#8212; for
example, the ‘sex compass’ quiz.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/04/facebook-drip-drip-drip">Called it</a>.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Guardian: &#8216;Far More Than 87 Million Facebook Users Had Data Compromised by Cambridge Analytica&#8217;’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/17/far-more-than-87m">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>50 Shades of Space Gray</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://9to5mac.com/2018/04/16/space-gray-odyssey/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtr" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/steeber-space-gray" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34767</id>
	<published>2018-04-16T22:21:18Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-17T19:47:46Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Michael Steeber, writing for 9to5Mac:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Yet, ubiquity has not brought consistency. Each new generation of
a product seems to bring with it a slightly different take on
space gray. Those with large device collections <a href="https://www.kirkville.com/the-many-shades-of-apples-space-gray/">have</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Mantia/status/947246392103223297">noted</a>
the discrepancies between shades, and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/3kidlx/apple_need_to_sort_out_what_they_mean_by_space/">discussions brew</a> online
over the term’s exact definition.</p>

<p>While subtle variations in material, texture, lighting, and even
the shape of a product can play tricks on the eyes, every device
Apple currently offers or has produced in space gray can be
grouped into one of several loosely defined categories. Below,
we’ve cataloged and categorized the vast universe of Apple’s
recent dark material finishes in an attempt to unravel the
mysteries of space gray.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unsurprisingly, I found this article a lot of fun. Certainly seems comprehensive.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘50 Shades of Space Gray’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/steeber-space-gray">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Spotify and Hulu Team Up for $13 Subscription Bundle</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://money.cnn.com/2018/04/11/technology/business/spotify-hulu-bundle-subscription/index.html" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtq" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/spotify-hulu-bundle" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34766</id>
	<published>2018-04-16T21:55:56Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-16T21:55:57Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Jackie Wattles, writing for CNN Tech:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The companies said Wednesday that a $12.99 per-month plan will get
you access to Spotify&#8217;s ad-free music streaming service and Hulu&#8217;s
basic package that allows you to stream TV shows and movies with
some ad breaks.</p>

<p>Paying for both services separately would set you back about $18
&#8212; $9.99 for Spotify Premium and $7.99 for Hulu.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Seems like a good deal and a smart partnership.</p>

<p>This is why I think Apple will roll its upcoming exclusive TV shows into Apple Music &#8212; people are naturally reluctant to sign up for yet another subscription. Spitball: $10 a month for Apple Music only (same as now); $15 for Apple Music and TV. Or maybe just give the shows to everyone at the current $10 &#8212; focus more on getting as many people signed up as possible, not extracting additional revenue from those who are signed up.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Spotify and Hulu Team Up for $13 Subscription Bundle’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/spotify-hulu-bundle">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>GrayKey iPhone Unlocker Poses Serious Security Concerns</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qtp" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/graykey-unlocker" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34765</id>
	<published>2018-04-16T21:48:37Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-16T21:48:38Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Thomas Reed, writing for the Malwarebytes Labs blog:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thanks to an anonymous source, we now know what this mysterious
device looks like, and how it works. And while the technology is a
good thing for law enforcement, it presents some significant
security risks.</p>

<p>GrayKey is a gray box, four inches wide by four inches deep by two
inches tall, with two lightning cables sticking out of the front.</p>

<p>Two iPhones can be connected at one time, and are connected for
about two minutes. After that, they are disconnected from the
device, but are not yet cracked. Some time later, the phones will
display a black screen with the passcode, among other information.
The exact length of time varies, taking about two hours in the
observations of our source. It can take up to three days or longer
for six-digit passcodes, according to Grayshift documents, and the
time needed for longer passphrases is not mentioned. Even disabled
phones can be unlocked, according to Grayshift.</p>

<p>After the device is unlocked, the full contents of the filesystem
are downloaded to the GrayKey device. From there, they can be
accessed through a web-based interface on a connected computer,
and downloaded for analysis. The full, unencrypted contents of the
keychain are also available for download.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So the phone is only connected to the box for two minutes, and then the phone itself displays the passcode after it&#8217;s cracked? If I&#8217;m reading this right, the box must jailbreak the iPhone and install the cracking software on the iPhone itself. I guess that would explain how they get around iOS&#8217;s (optional) wipe-after-10-wrong-guesses feature, as well as the escalating delays after a few wrong guesses.</p>

<p>Hopefully Apple can figure out how to fix this jailbreak. If you&#8217;re concerned about this, <a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/59jq8a/how-to-make-a-secure-iphone-passcode-6-digits">you ought to switch to a stronger alphanumeric passphrase</a>.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘GrayKey iPhone Unlocker Poses Serious Security Concerns’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/graykey-unlocker">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
	<title>Nikola Tesla Predicted the Smartphone in 1926</title>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kottke.org/18/04/nikola-tesla-predicted-the-smartphone-in-1926" />
	<link rel="shorturl" type="text/html" href="http://df4.us/qto" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/tesla-smart-phone" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/linked//6.34764</id>
	<published>2018-04-16T19:22:32Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-16T19:22:33Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Remarkably prescient predictions from Tesla, in a 1926 interview with Collier&#8217;s:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When wireless is perfectly applied the whole earth will be
converted into a huge brain, which in fact it is, all things being
particles of a real and rhythmic whole. We shall be able to
communicate with one another instantly, irrespective of distance.
Not only this, but through television and telephony we shall see
and hear one another as perfectly as though we were face to face,
despite intervening distances of thousands of miles; and the
instruments through which we shall be able to do his will be
amazingly simple compared with our present telephone. A man will
be able to carry one in his vest pocket.</p>

<p>We shall be able to witness and hear events &#8212; the inauguration of
a President, the playing of a world series game, the havoc of an
earthquake or the terror of a battle &#8212; just as though we were
present.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Streaming video is getting to be old hat. It&#8217;s human nature that we take every breakthrough for granted after just a few years. But sometimes when I&#8217;m watching a live baseball game on my phone while I&#8217;m walking around, it strikes me just how futuristic it would seem to my younger self.</p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Nikola Tesla Predicted the Smartphone in 1926’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/04/16/tesla-smart-phone">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
  </entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/the_impact_of_leaks" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qtg" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34756</id>
	<published>2018-04-13T19:06:52Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-13T19:30:16Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">Apple is not fucking around regarding leaks.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Gurman has obtained <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-13/apple-warns-employees-to-stop-leaking-information-to-media">a copy of a company-wide memo on leaking, and published it at Bloomberg</a>. I suggest skipping Gurman&#8217;s summary of the memo and scrolling down to the memo itself. Curiously, Gurman doesn&#8217;t say when the memo was posted and he omits its headline. I&#8217;ve heard the memo was posted on Monday this week, and the headline was &#8220;The Impact of Leaks&#8221;. Some observations, starting with the opening:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Last month, Apple caught and fired the employee responsible for
leaking details from an internal, confidential meeting about
Apple’s software roadmap. Hundreds of software engineers were in
attendance, and thousands more within the organization received
details of its proceedings. One person betrayed their trust.</p>

<p>The employee who leaked the meeting to a reporter later told Apple
investigators that he did it because he thought he wouldn’t be
discovered. But people who leak &#8212; whether they’re Apple
employees, contractors or suppliers &#8212; do get caught and they’re
getting caught faster than ever.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Gurman doesn&#8217;t mention that the meeting was leaked to Gurman himself &#8212; the person who leaked <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/apple-is-said-to-push-back-some-key-iphone-software-features">this story</a> was caught and fired. I can see why Gurman and Bloomberg might not want to emphasize that.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Investments by Apple have had an enormous impact on the company’s
ability to identify and catch leakers. Just before last
September’s special event, an employee leaked a link to the gold
master of iOS 11 to the press, again believing he wouldn’t be
caught. The unreleased OS detailed soon-to-be-announced software
and hardware including iPhone X. Within days, the leaker was
identified through an internal investigation and fired.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The iOS 11 GM leak <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2017/09/09/appl-iphone-8-iphone-8-plus-iphone-x/">revealed the name &#8220;iPhone X&#8221;</a>. It also confirmed features like Face ID and wireless charging, but the name was the big one. Face ID and wireless charging had been rumored for a year, but until that leak just three days before the event, we had no idea what Apple was going to call its new phones. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Global Security’s digital forensics also helped catch several
employees who were feeding confidential details about new products
including iPhone X, iPad Pro and AirPods to a blogger at 9to5Mac.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It&#8217;s unclear which stories at 9to5Mac this is about, but the AirPods story is probably <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2016/01/08/iphone-7-wireless-headphones-beats/">this one</a>, which was a huge scoop published 9 months before AirPods were announced &#8212; by none other than Mark Gurman. It seems possible that every single specific example cited by Apple in this memo was someone leaking to Mark Gurman. Makes you wonder who had the balls to send this memo to him. We&#8217;ll be getting into <em>Inception</em> territory if the leaker of the memo on leakers getting fired for leaking to Gurman gets fired for leaking it to Gurman.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Leakers do not simply lose their jobs at Apple. In some cases,
they face jail time and massive fines for network intrusion and
theft of trade secrets both classified as federal crimes. In 2017,
Apple caught 29 leakers. 12 of those were arrested. Among those
were Apple employees, contractors and some partners in Apple’s
supply chain. These people not only lose their jobs, they can face
extreme difficulty finding employment elsewhere. “The potential
criminal consequences of leaking are real,” says Tom Moyer of
Global Security, “and that can become part of your personal and
professional identity forever.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Getting fired for leaking &#8212; we all knew that happened. But this is the first I&#8217;ve heard of leakers being prosecuted criminally and going to jail. Apple is not fucking around regarding leaks.</p>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ Company-Wide Apple Memo on ‘The Impact of Leaks’ Leaks</title></entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/zuckerbergs_notes" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qt8" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34748</id>
	<published>2018-04-11T21:20:25Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-12T18:04:16Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">Zuckerberg should stick to the “some companies work hard to charge you more, other work hard to charge you less” angle. Trying to say that Apple is in the same boat as Facebook on the privacy front is simply laughable.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>During a break in Mark Zuckerberg&#8217;s testimony before Congress yesterday, Zuckerberg inexplicably left his prepared notes &#8212; PR-approved talking points for anticipated lines of questioning &#8212; behind on the table. Associated Press photographer Andrew Harnik snapped a photo of them before a Facebook aide could close them, and it was <a href="https://twitter.com/becket/status/983846618263891968">widely shared on Twitter</a>. The AP&#8217;s Behind the News site has <a href="https://blog.ap.org/behind-the-news/how-i-got-that-photo-of-zuckerbergs-notes">a piece today on how Harnik got the shot</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Once I was able to sit down at the end of the event and see the
response from Twitter and read what was in Zuckerberg’s notes, I
realized this was pretty important information. I read some
responses on Twitter &#8212; the photo was congratulated and celebrated
by many fellow journalists, while others thought it was an
invasion of privacy. Others simply saw the irony of someone’s
notes being shared so publicly during a major congressional
hearing on data privacy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The section in the talking points that got my attention, as well as that of <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxTemkin/status/983865019136954368">many others</a>, regarded Tim Cook and Apple. It never actually came up during his testimony, but Zuckerberg and Facebook were clearly anticipating questions pertaining to <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2018/03/28/tim-cook-mark-zuckerberg-comments/">Tim Cook&#8217;s recent remarks on Facebook&#8217;s business model and privacy</a>. Basically, the whole &#8220;<em>If you&#8217;re not the customer, then you&#8217;re the product</em>&#8221; argument.</p>

<p>Here is the section from Zuckerberg&#8217;s notes, verbatim:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Tim Cook on biz model</p>

<ul>
<li>Bezos: &#8220;Companies that work hard to charge you more and
companies that work hard to charge you less.&#8221;</li>
<li>At FB, we try hard to charge you less. In fact, we&#8217;re free.</li>
<li>[On data, we&#8217;re similar. When you install an app on your iPhone,
you give it access to some information, just like when you login
with FB.</li>
<li>Lots of stories about apps misusing Apple data, never seen Apple
notify people.</li>
<li>Important to hold everyone to the same standard.]</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Zuckerberg used the first two points &#8212; citing <a href="https://thenextweb.com/mobile/2011/09/28/amazons-bezos-we-worked-hard-to-charge-you-less-for-kindle-fire/">Jeff Bezos&#8217;s quote about there being two types of companies</a>, and asserting that Facebook is decidedly on the &#8220;working hard to charge you less&#8221; side of that equation &#8212; when he was asked about Cook&#8217;s remarks during his (excellent) <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/2/17185052/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-interview-fake-news-bots-cambridge">podcast interview with Vox&#8217;s Ezra Klein</a> last week. The speciousness of that defense was the subject of <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/users_and_customers">the column I wrote last week</a>, so I don&#8217;t need to cover it here.</p>

<p>The other three points &#8212; hoo-boy. To be fair, these are only prepared notes. Zuckerberg didn&#8217;t say them, and we don&#8217;t know if he would have if questioned about Cook&#8217;s remarks. So it&#8217;s not fair to treat them as though they&#8217;re actually quotes from Zuckerberg.<sup id="fnr1-2018-04-11"><a href="#fn1-2018-04-11">1</a></sup> But what a pile of horseshit they would have been if he had.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>On data, we&#8217;re similar. When you install an app on your iPhone,
you give it access to some information, just like when you login [<em>sic</em>]
with FB.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There is almost nothing similar about how Apple and Facebook treat user data. Installing an app on an iPhone is nothing like signing in to Facebook. Yes, apps on iOS do get access to <em>some</em> data. But anything remotely private is only accessible to apps after the user has granted explicit permission for this access, and such access is also easily and clearly revokable in the Settings app&#8217;s Privacy section. Apple provides the user with clear control.</p>

<p>As for where Zuckerberg might have gone with the item about &#8220;Lots of stories about apps misusing Apple data&#8221;, I&#8217;m not sure what that&#8217;s about. Maybe something like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/2/7/2782947/path-ios-app-user-information-collected-privacy">the 2012 story where the now-nearly-forgotten app Path was caught uploading users&#8217; entire contacts database to their servers</a>? That was bad for user privacy, and Apple can be blamed for having allowed apps to access the address book without the user&#8217;s permission. But Apple responded, quickly, by making access to the address book something that required the user&#8217;s permission. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/3/17/2879207/os-x-10-8-mountain-lion-privacy">They made the same change on MacOS too</a>.) </p>

<p>Apple was, at worst, naive about what apps would do with unfettered access to users&#8217; address books. Facebook is facing criticism today &#8212; <a href="https://www.recode.net/2018/4/10/17220060/facebook-trust-major-tech-company">and losing its users&#8217; trust</a> &#8212; not because they&#8217;ve been naive about privacy, but because they&#8217;ve been devious about it.</p>

<p>Nobody is arguing that Apple collects too much data about users. If anything, I see some people arguing the opposite: that Apple is falling behind in the machine learning race because they don&#8217;t collect and aggregate <em>enough</em> data. And as for third-party apps collecting privacy-invasive data from devices, we now know that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones/">Facebook has been collecting phone call and SMS messaging history from Android devices</a> &#8212; but not iOS, because iOS has <em>never</em> allowed third-party apps access to phone call or text messaging data.</p>

<p>Zuckerberg should stick to the &#8220;some companies work hard to charge you more, other work hard to charge you less&#8221; angle. Trying to argue that Apple is in the same boat as Facebook on the privacy front is simply laughable.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1-2018-04-11">
<p>I&#8217;m curious about the brackets that surround the last three points. (<a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2018/04/zuckerbergs-notes.jpg">Close-up image</a>.) At first I thought they were typos, because they&#8217;re located within the bullet points. But I suspect the bullet points were generated by a word processor like Word or Pages, where the bullet glyphs are auto-generated by the word processor and aren&#8217;t editable. I strongly suspect that those brackets are meant to group these three points together.&nbsp;<a href="#fnr1-2018-04-11"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">&#x21A9;&#xFE0E;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ Regarding Mark Zuckerberg’s Unused Talking Points on Tim Cook and Apple</title></entry><entry>
	
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jamf.com/lp/daringfireball-jamf-now/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=2018-15 " />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qt0" />
	<link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2018/04/jamf_now_easily_manage_apple_d" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018:/feeds/sponsors//11.34740</id>
	<author><name>Daring Fireball Department of Commerce</name></author>
	<published>2018-04-09T20:30:48-04:00</published>
	<updated>2018-04-09T20:30:50-04:00</updated>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>It is essential that you secure the Apple devices in your organization. With Jamf Now you can get inventory, configure Wi-Fi and email settings, deploy applications, protect company data, and even lock or wipe a device from anywhere.</p>

<p>Jamf Now secures your devices so you can focus on your business. No IT experience needed.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.jamf.com/lp/daringfireball-jamf-now/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=2018-15">Daring Fireball readers can create an account and manage three devices for free</a>. Forever. After that, each additional device is just $2 per month. <a href="https://www.jamf.com/lp/daringfireball-jamf-now/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=2018-15">Create your free account today!</a></p>

<div>
<a  title="Permanent link to ‘Jamf Now: Easily Manage Apple Devices in Minutes’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2018/04/jamf_now_easily_manage_apple_d">&nbsp;★&nbsp;</a>
</div>

	]]></content>
	<title>[Sponsor] Jamf Now: Easily Manage Apple Devices in Minutes</title></entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/wsj_apple_pay" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qsg" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34720</id>
	<published>2018-04-04T03:59:00Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-04T05:38:49Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">A three-act train wreck of a story.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-insists-iphone-users-enroll-in-apple-pay-with-a-red-badge-that-wont-go-away-1522753200?mod=e2tw">Tripp Mickle, writing for The Wall Street Journal</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple Inc. is nagging iPhone users to enroll in its mobile-payment
service with a persistent red circle badge. The strategy has
worked with some, but is irritating others who say it is
heavy-handed and exploits the tech giant’s clout in ways that
could disadvantage rivals.</p>

<p>The tactic, part of the iPhone’s latest operating software
launched last fall, is subtle. Users who opt not to input
credit-card information for Apple Pay when setting up their phones
now constantly see the red circle over their settings icon,
indicating their setup is incomplete. Some users also periodically
get notification reminders that go away only once they start the
enrollment process.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mickle has a point here. This does annoy people who, for whatever reason, don&#8217;t want to set up Apple Pay. <a href="https://m.imore.com/how-stop-apple-pay-pestering-you">There is a way to dismiss the red badge</a>, but it&#8217;s not obvious how, because the button you have to tap says &#8220;Set Up Apple Pay&#8221;. (After that, you tap &#8220;Cancel&#8221; or &#8220;Set Up Later in Wallet&#8221;.) It is inscrutably counterintuitive to need to tap a button that says &#8220;Set Up Apple Pay&#8221; when your intention is to stop being nagged to set it up because you <em>don&#8217;t want to set up Apple Pay</em>.</p>

<p>But the Journal article never explains that you can turn off this red badge. As Mickle tells it, the only way to turn off the badge is to sign up for Apple Pay. That&#8217;s just wrong, and renders the remainder of his article moot.</p>

<p>In act 2, the article turns weird:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Though payment analysts say the service speeds up checkout times
and is more secure than traditional cards, Apple Pay has struggled
to earn broad adoption in the U.S. Many remain skeptical that it
is more secure, including Jack Frederick, a 29-year-old
professional comedian from Queens, N.Y., who prefers using his
credit card directly.</p>

<p>“This is the most aggressive they’ve ever been,” said Mr.
Frederick, who has had a red badge over his iPhone settings since
updating his software in mid-January. He said the notification has
made him consider trading his iPhone 6 for a Google Pixel. “All
that from one dot,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Experts say using Apple Pay is faster and more secure than using a credit card, but here&#8217;s a 29-year-old comedian who thinks otherwise. Who wouldn&#8217;t take credit card security advice from a completely random guy on the street?</p>

<p>I do think Apple has a marketing problem with Apple Pay, though. I can tell from talking to family members that a lot of people just don&#8217;t see why they should try Apple Pay, because they have no idea how it works or why they&#8217;d want to use it. And I think they worry that because it&#8217;s new and sort of science-fiction-y it will make their credit card <em>more</em> likely to be hacked, when the truth is the opposite. I think Apple needs more ads that explain and demonstrate the convenience and indisputable security advantages of using Apple Pay instead of a credit card, and the extraordinary convenience of Apple Pay Cash. I can see how a lot of people think, &#8220;<em>Eh, I&#8217;ll just keep using my credit card</em>&#8221; when they&#8217;re paying for something in a retail store. But Apple Pay Cash could be enough to get these people to set up Apple Pay.</p>

<p>Anyway, in act three, Mickle takes things to the absurd:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Everyone is doing essentially the same trick,” said Roger Kay, an
analyst with Endpoint Technologies Associates. “It’s really
antitrust behavior.”</p>

<p>Mr. Kay compared Apple Pay setup badges and notifications to
Microsoft Corp. bundling its Internet Explorer browser with
Windows in the 1990s &#8212; a strategy the Justice Department
successfully sued to stop on antitrust grounds saying it hurt
rivals. “They used to have actual behavioral remedies and say you
can’t do this,” Mr. Kay said.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is a ridiculous comparison in several ways, but I&#8217;ll point out just one. With the benefit of 20 years of hindsight, it&#8217;s now clear that one aspect of Microsoft&#8217;s defense was correct: web browsers do belong built into operating systems at the system level. <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2018/04/safari-required.png">Good luck removing Safari</a> from MacOS or iOS. I wish you even better luck removing Chrome from a Chromebook.</p>

<p>Netscape didn&#8217;t lose to IE because IE was built into Windows; it lost because IE was better. And when first Firefox and then Chrome came along, they thrived on Windows because they were better than IE.</p>

<p>Apple Pay, as conceived, has to be built into the OS. By Kay&#8217;s argument, most of the built-in features in <em>any</em> OS are anticompetitive. What new features <em>could</em> be added to iOS without hurting some sort of <a href="https://justgetflux.com/ios.html">competitor</a>?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple declined to comment on potential antitrust concerns.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Probably because they were stifling laughter.</p>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ A Really Dumb Wall Street Journal Story on Apple Pay That Almost Makes a Good Point at the Very Beginning</title></entry><entry>
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/04/users_and_customers" />
	<link rel="shorturl" href="http://df4.us/qsb" />
	<id>tag:daringfireball.net,2018://1.34715</id>
	<published>2018-04-02T23:36:31Z</published>
	<updated>2018-04-02T23:36:32Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>John Gruber</name>
		<uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri>
	</author>
	<summary type="text">The linguistic trick Zuckerberg pulls here is that nowhere in the entire interview does he mention the words *user* or *customer*.</summary>
	<content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Fascinating, wide-ranging podcast interview (with an excellent transcript) <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/2/17185052/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-interview-fake-news-bots-cambridge">between Vox&#8217;s Ezra Klein and Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Klein</strong>: One of the things that has been coming up a lot in the
conversation is whether the business model of monetizing user
attention is what is letting in a lot of these problems. Tim Cook,
the CEO of Apple, gave an interview the other day and he was asked
what he would do if he was in your shoes. He said, “I wouldn’t be
in this situation,” and argued that Apple sells products to users,
it doesn’t sell users to advertisers, and so it’s a sounder
business model that doesn’t open itself to these problems.</p>

<p>Do you think part of the problem here is the business model where
attention ends up dominating above all else, and so anything that
can engage has powerful value within the ecosystem?</p>

<p><strong>Zuckerberg</strong>: You know, I find that argument, that if you’re not
paying that somehow we can’t care about you, to be extremely glib
and not at all aligned with the truth. The reality here is that if
you want to build a service that helps connect everyone in the
world, then there are a lot of people who can’t afford to pay. And
therefore, as with a lot of media, having an advertising-supported
model is the only rational model that can support building this
service to reach people. [&#8230;]</p>

<p>But if you want to build a service which is not just serving rich
people, then you need to have something that people can afford. I
thought Jeff Bezos had an excellent saying on this in one of his
Kindle launches a number of years back. He said, “There are
companies that work hard to charge you more, and there are
companies that work hard to charge you less.” And at Facebook, we
are squarely in the camp of the companies that work hard to charge
you less and provide a free service that everyone can use.</p>

<p>I don’t think at all that that means that we don’t care about
people. To the contrary, I think it’s important that we don’t all
get Stockholm syndrome and let the companies that work hard to
charge you more convince you that they actually care more about
you. Because that sounds ridiculous to me.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There is certainly something to Zuckerberg&#8217;s argument here, but the speciousness of the way he formulates it is that a company working hard to charge you more money <em>is</em> undeniably incentivized to care more about you, <em>if</em> you can afford their product or service. I think it’s undeniable that Apple cares more about the hundreds of millions of people who buy its products than Facebook cares about any of its billions of users.</p>

<p>The more apt Tim Cook quote that applies here <a href="https://gadgets.ndtv.com/internet/news/tim-cook-to-google-users-youre-not-the-customer-youre-the-product-594242">is this long-standing internet adage</a>: &#8220;When an online service is free, you&#8217;re not the customer. You&#8217;re the product.&#8221; Amazon is undeniably focused on low prices. But Facebook doesn&#8217;t charge low prices &#8212; they charge high prices. To their customers: advertisers. And <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/234056/facebooks-average-advertising-revenue-per-user/">a cursory look at their financials</a> indicates they&#8217;ve been working hard to raise those prices.</p>

<p>The linguistic trick Zuckerberg pulls here is that nowhere in the entire interview does he mention the words <em>user</em> or <em>customer</em>. He only says <em>you</em> (in the plural sense) and <em>people</em>. That&#8217;s a dodge, because unlike Apple &#8212; and Amazon &#8212; Facebook&#8217;s users are not its customers &#8212; and most of the controversies they are dealing with today all stem from the fact that they favored their customers (advertisers willing to pay ever-higher sums for ever-more-invasively-targeted ads) at the expense of their users.</p>



    ]]></content>
  <title>★ Users and Customers</title></entry></feed><!-- THE END -->
